JAVA/J2EE DEVELOPER

Summary

Specialized in Core Java and Java/JEE based Full Stack & technologies, including designing, development, maintenance, technical consultancy for last 5 years. *Extensively worked in the capacity of a Technical consultant / Sr Developer / Sr Analyst with excellent business domain experience in the analysis, development and maintenance of Business applications using J2EE, MVC design pattern, Struts, Java (JDK), JDBC, Swing, Java Servlets, EJB, JSP, HTML, XML, XSL, XSLT, Hibernate, Spring, Web Services, JavaScript, JQueiry, AngularJs, AJAX, JSF.JDBC, Oracle 11g/10g/9i, SQL, PL/SQL. *Spring framework, MVC, Struts framework, Java Server Faces, Hibernate persistence framework, UML design methodologies, Eclipse/JBuilder IDE for developing, debugging and deploying applications on BEA WebLogic, Jboss (Containers for Java EE), tomcat for both Windows as well as Linux.

Experience

12/2015 to Current

Java/J2EE Developer Synechron Inc - Harrison, NY

- UPS) is the world's largest package delivery company and a provider of supply chain management solutions.
- The Operations Label and Forms Service (OLAFS), a Windows based Web Service where clients will request for a label/form via a SOAP-based interface.
- The service will be deployed on a Windows 2008 server with IIS and will be available to internal clients.
- OLAFS will leverage an existing label printing component (FOSS) and report designer (Microsoft Reports) for forms.
- Labels will be available as EPL2, ZPL2, PNG, GIF, JPEG, or PDF files.
- Forms will be available as PDF, Excel, or TIFF files.
- It will handle URC and Maxicode Compression and will support 4x6, 4x8, 2x4 label formats.
- It will support multiple languages.

03/2014 to 11/2015

Java/J2EE Developer Synechron Inc - Jersey City, NJ

- The Barclays Capital Aggregate Bond Index is a Market Capitalization-weighted index, meaning the securities in the index are weighted according to the market size of each bond type.
- Most U.S.
- traded investment grade bonds are represented.
- The Price Challenge System is a real-time web application used by the Index Production and Index Pricing Teams of Barclays Risk Analytics & Index Solutions(BRAIS) group.
- It provides a single user interface for the production and pricing teams across the globe to capture the price challenges received from clients, record the resolutions provided and communicating the resolutions back to the clients.
- The recorded information is available in the form of Reports and Statistics, thus providing a summary of the data useful for senior management reviews and audit requirements.
- Essentially, it eliminates a lot of manual inefficiencies in the day to day activities of the users involved in recording, evaluating, validating, resolving and responding to the price challenges raised by clients.
- It is tightly integrated with several other BRAIS systems and augments the index solutions, workflow.
- In this regard, it is one of the mission critical applications for the BRIAS group.

06/2013 to 02/2014

Java/J2EE Developer Synechron Inc - Plano, TX

- Guy Carpenter helps its clients achieve profitable growth with a powerful combination of specialized reinsurance broking expertise, strategic advisory services, and industry leading analytics.
- The project Analytics (GC ProfitPointPlus2.0) are a J2EE application which deals with fetching details of the policies with filters contains States. County etc.
- For the clients to use with more flexible and reusability.

10/2012 to 05/2013

Java/J2EE Developer Synechron Inc - San Francisco, CA

- Sempra U.S.
- Gas & Power develops clean power solutions in markets throughout the U.S.
- with a focus on zero and low-emission fuels.
- The company operates more than 1,500 megawatts of renewable and natural gas-fueled power plants, including one of the largest photo voltaic solar facilities in the U.S.
- The project RE/RC(Rate Comparison/ Rate enrollment) are a JEE application which deals with enrollment of new customers and managing their accounts and meters.

07/2009 to 05/2010

Software Engineer Nortonlifelock Inc. - AZ, State

- Web Applications most targeted for the intruders to compromise because everything that is supposed to be confidential, exposed to the internet.
- This can be avoided by doing the same as what the intruder tries to do as an initial step to identify the confidential files saved on the web

server.

- Rather, it also lists out the available URL's which the application uses or has as a part of the Web Application.
- A Bot is designed for the targeted work and so this Bot tries to crawl the whole website just by taking the main URL as an input and lists all the pages or things, which it's getting connected to.

Education

2012

Masters: Computer Technology Eastern Illinois University USA GPA: 3.1/4.0 Computer Technology GPA: 3.1/4.0

Bachelors : Computer Science and Information Technology, JNTU India Eastern Illinois University GPA: 3.4/4.0 Computer Science and Information Technology, JNTU India GPA: 3.4/4.0

Skills

photo, bonds, Carpenter, clients, delivery, senior management, focus, Forms, GC, IIS, J2EE, managing, Market, Excel, Windows, natural gas, PDF, policies, Pricing, real-time, recording, Research, securities, SOAP, Statistics, strategic, supply chain management, type, user interface, Web Applications, web server, website, workflow